airfarewatchdog.com 2015-12-11

# Privacy Statement - Airfarewatchdog

**AIRFAREWATCHDOG PRIVACY POLICY**

 Airfarewatchdog.com is a travel information service. We do not sell travel products or services. We provide you with information about third-party travel suppliers' offers, and we link you to their sites. Our Web site is is owned and operated by Smarter Travel LLC.  More details about Airfarewatchdog can be found below under “How you can contact us.” 

We understand that providing information online involves a great deal of trust on your part.  We take this trust very seriously, and make it a high priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal information you provide to us.  Before submitting your personal information to our Web site, please read this Policy carefully to learn about our privacy practices. By visiting Airfarewatchdog’s Web site, www.Airfarewatchdog.com, you are accepting the practices described herein.  

  * What information we collect from you
  * How we use your information
  * With whom we share your information
  * How you can access your information
  * Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information
  * How we protect your information
  * Children’s privacy
  * External links
  * Visiting our Web site from outside the United States
  * Your California privacy rights
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * How you can contact us 

**What information we collect from you**  
In General.  We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. This includes information that can identify you ("personal information"), including your first and last name, telephone number, postal and e-mail addresses, user name and password.  We may also request information about your travel plans, style, and preferences, including meal requests, seat selection, frequent flyer/hotel/car rental program information, and flight class, luggage, and ticketing options.  You can choose not to provide information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to enjoy the benefits of being a registered member.  For example, only registered members are able to post travel reviews, participate in discussion forums, e-mail Airfarewatchdog content to themselves and others, access members-only newsletters and travel planning content, and enter surveys, contests, or sweepstakes.  In addition, some information is also required in order for you to ask us a question or initiate other transactions on our site.

Information About Others.  You will have the opportunity to provide contact information for other people through our Web site. You should obtain the consent of other individuals prior to providing Airfarewatchdog with their personal information.

Information from Other Sources.  We also may periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from affiliated entities, business partners and other independent third-party sources and add it to other information about you.  For example, if you visit Airfarewatchdog by “clicking-through” from a site operated by one of our business partners, and you have registered with that partner, then information about you that you have provided to that partner may be shared with us.  Examples of other information we may receive include contact information and demographic information.

Automatic Information.  We automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit Airfarewatchdog.  For example, we will collect session data, including your IP address, Web browser software, and referring Web site.  We also may collect information about your online activity, such as content viewed and pages visited.  One of our goals in collecting this automatic information is to help us understand the interests of our users and customize your user experience.

Cookies and Other Web Technologies. Cookies are small data text files and can be stored on your computer’s hard drive (if your Web browser permits).  Airfarewatchdog.com and its affiliated websites use cookies for the following general purposes:

  * To help us recognize your browser as a previous visitor and save and remember any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our site.  For example, if you register on our site, we may use cookies to remember your registration information, so you do not need to log into our site each time you visit.  We also may record your password in a cookie, if you checked the box entitled "Save this password for automatic sign-in."  Please note that member IDs, passwords, and any other account-related data included in such cookies are encrypted for security purposes.
  * To help us customize the content, website experience, and advertisements provided to you on our websites and on other websites across the Internet.  For example, when you access a web page, a cookie is automatically set by us, our service providers, or our partners to recognize your browser as you navigate on the Internet and to present you with information and advertising based on your apparent interests.  See Display of Advertising/Your Choices [A1] for more information about our online advertising practices and your choices. 
  * To help measure and research the effectiveness of website features and offerings, advertisements, and e-mail communications (by determining which e-mails you open and act upon). 

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers should tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable most types of cookies.  Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to access many of the travel tools offered on our sites. 

Our sites also may use Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or Web bugs), which are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, that are placed in the code of a Web page.  We use Web beacons to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our sites to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party Web site, and to improve site performance.  We also may allow our service providers to use Web beacons to help us understand which emails have been opened by recipients and to track the visitor traffic and actions on our site.  This helps us measure the effectiveness of our content and other offerings.

Display of Advertising/Your Choices 

_Data collected to serve you with relevant advertising_

Airfarewatchdog and its affiliated websites are committed to providing you with relevant content and information across our sites.  To do this, we may collect information about your travel-related searches, such as whether you are looking for airline flights or hotels, and use this information to serve you with ads on our sites or elsewhere online that match your apparent interests.  So, for example, if you search for a flight to Florida on Airfarewatchdog.com, you may see an ad for a Florida travel package on Airfarewatchdog.com or on another website you visit. 

We do not share your personal information (such as email addresses) with unaffiliated third parties so they can serve you with advertisements.  You can choose not to receive relevant online advertising on other Web sites, based on your travel-related searches on Airfarewatchdog.com by clicking here.  [A2] 

_Data collected by business partners and ad networks to serve you with relevant advertising_

Many of the advertisements you see on the Airfarewatchdog.com family of sites are served by Airfarewatchdog.com or its service providers.  But we also allow third parties to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies[A3] .  These third parties include (1) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on our sites, and (2) advertising networks, who collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of the advertisements they place on many different Web sites on the Internet.  The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests. 

Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  Some of these companies are members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies.  To learn more, please click here. 

**How we use your information**  
Airfarewatchdog uses the information we collect about you for the following general purposes: for registration and to manage your account, including to facilitate your access to and use of our site; to communicate with you in general, including to provide information about Airfarewatchdog and invitations from the Airfarewatchdog community; to enable us to publish your reviews, forum posts, and other content to the Airfarewatchdog community; to respond to your questions and comments; to measure interest in and improve our products, services, and Web site; to notify you about special offers and products or services available from us or our partners that may be of interest to you; to otherwise customize your experience with Airfarewatchdog; to solicit information from you, including through surveys; to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; to enforce our Terms of Use; and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection.

If you have signed up as the owner or manager of a vacation rental, or listed your vacation rental property in our Destination Resources section, we will send you e-mail messages at the email address you provide to us.

Please review "Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information[A4] " below.

**With whom we share your information**  
Airfarewatchdog may share your information with the following entities:

  * Third-party vendors who provide services or functions on our behalf, including business analytics, customer service, marketing, distribution of surveys or sweepstakes programs, and fraud prevention.  We may also authorize third-party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including as necessary to operate features of our website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests.  Third-party vendors have access to and may collect information only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose. 
  * Business partners with whom we may offer products or services in conjunction.  You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear either with ours or separately. If you choose to access these optional services, we may share information about you, including your personal information, with those partners.  Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party business partners. 
  * Affiliated Web sites.  If you were referred to Airfarewatchdog from another Web site, we may share your registration information, such as your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number and travel preferences, about you with that referring Web site.  We have not placed limitations on the referring Web sites’ use of personal information and we encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Web site that referred you to Airfarewatchdog.
  * Companies within our corporate family.  We may share your personal information within the Airfarewatchdog Media Group, as well as with our parent companies and domestic and international corporate affiliate companies and websites (including DaoDao.com).  This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services, both travel-related and other, which might interest you.  To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy.  They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial e-mail they send to choose not to receive such e-mail messages in the future. 

We also may share your information:

  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law.  In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. 
  * When we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Airfarewatchdog, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Service and other agreements. 
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy. 

If you choose to create a profile on Airfarewatchdog, certain information in your profile will be publicly viewable and identifiable via your screen name.  You will have the ability to view your profile as members of the public will see it.  Additionally, if you choose to participate in our member-to-member communications programs, other Airfarewatchdog members may contact you by using Airfarewatchdog as an intermediary; however, Airfarewatchdog will not share your email address with any other members nor display it any public manner.  All Airfarewatchdog members have the option to turn off the member-to-member communication features at any time.

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when personal information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors.  For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors our Web site receives or the most popular hotels and vacation destinations.  This information does not contain any personal information and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.

**How you can access your information**  
We take reasonable steps to ensure that your information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, and complete.  You can close your Airfarewatchdog.com account by contacting us at the phone number listed below or by selecting "Unsubscribe Me" on the Newsletters page.  Please note that after you close an account, you will not be able to sign in or access any of your personal information.  However, you can open a new account at any time.  Please also note that we may retain certain information associated with your account in our archives, including for analytical purposes as well as for recordkeeping integrity. 

**Your choices with respect to collection and use of your information**

  * As discussed above, you can choose not to provide us with any information, although it may be needed to take advantage of certain features offered on Airfarewatchdog. 
  * You also can add or update information and close your account as described above. 
  * As a registered Airfarewatchdog member, you can modify your e-mail subscription choices at any time on the Member Profile page.  Whether registered as a Airfarewatchdog member or not, you also will be given the opportunity to unsubscribe from promotional messages in any such e-mail we send.  Please note that we reserve the right to send you other communications, including service announcements, administrative messages, and surveys relating either to your Airfarewatchdog account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.
  * Email Communications. Airfarewatchdog.com wants to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our Web site.  One way we do this is by sending you e-mail messages that contain information about your apparent travel-related interests.  For example, if you search for a flight to New York, or New York hotels or reviews on Airfarewatchdog.com, we may send you an email message reminding you about special airfare or hotel offers in New York.  Similarly, if you receive an email about New York travel and demonstrate an interest in New York hotels, flights, or local travel reviews by affirmatively clicking on a link about New York hotels in the email, you may receive an email about New York hotel or flight offers.  We believe these email messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites.  Please note that you will have the opportunity to choose not to receive these email messages in any such email we send. 
  * The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether.  Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies from Airfarewatchdog, you will not be able to access portions of our site. 

**How we protect your information**  
We want you to feel confident about using Airfarewatchdog, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect.  While no Web site can guarantee security, we have implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect the personal information you provide to us.  For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.  In addition, we use encryption when transmitting your personal information between your system and ours, and we employ firewalls and intrusion detection systems to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your information.

**Children's privacy**  
Airfarewatchdog is a general audience site and does not offer services directed to children.  Should an individual whom we know to be a child under age 13 send personal information to us, we will delete or destroy such information as soon as reasonably possible.

**External links**  
If any part of the Airfarewatchdog Web site links you to other Web sites, those external Web sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy.  We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other Web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

**Visiting our Web sites from outside the United States**

If you are visiting our Web site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated.  The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that Airfarewatchdog does take steps pursuant to laws in the United States to ensure that your privacy is protected.  By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy. ** **

**Your California privacy rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please email [membersupport@Airfarewatchdog.com](mailto:membersupport@tripadvisor.com "blocked::mailto:membersupport@tripadvisor.com"). 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Airfarewatchdog may update this Privacy Policy in the future.  We will notify our members about material changes to this Privacy Policy by either sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our Web site.

**How you can contact us**  
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: 

Email:  [privacy@Airfarewatchdog.com](mailto:privacy@airfarewatchdog.com).

Smarter Travel Media LLC  
Attn: Airfarewatchdog.com  
226 Causeway Street, Third Floor  
Boston, MA 02114

This Privacy Policy is effective as of [insert date].[A5] 

* * *

 [A1]Link to section in the pp.

 [A2]Link to NAI opt-out here.  <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>

 [A3]Link to separate cookie section.

 [A4]Insert link

 [A5]Insert date of posting.

Below you will find the updated Privacy Policy for Airfarewatchdog.com, effective June 11, 2008.

We understand that providing information online involves trust on your part. We take this trust very seriously, and make it our highest priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal information you provide to us. Please read the following policy to learn about our privacy practices.By visiting our U.S. Web site, www.Airfarewatchdog.com, you are accepting the practices described herein.

  * What information we collect from you
  * How we use your information
  * With whom we share your information
  * How you can access your information
  * Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information
  * How we protect your information
  * Children's privacy
  * External links
  * Visiting our Web site from outside the United States
  * Your California privacy rights
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * How you can contact us

**What information we collect from you**

In General. We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. This includes information that can identify you ("personal information"), including your first and last name and your e-mail address. We may also request information about your location and travel preferences. You can choose not to provide information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to register as a member; subscribe to a newsletter; participate in a user forum; comment on a blog or article; purchase products or services; complete a traveler profile; participate in a survey, contest, or sweepstakes; ask us a question; or initiate other transactions on our site.

Information from Other Sources. We also may periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from affiliated entities, business partners and other independent third-party sources and add it to our account information. Examples of information we may receive include: updated delivery and address information, purchase history, and demographic information.

Automatic Information. We automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit Airfarewatchdog.com. For example, we will collect your IP address, Web browser software (such as Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer), and referring Web site. We also may collect information about your online activity, such as airfares viewed and subscription activity. One of our goals in collecting this automatic information is to help customize your user experience.

Cookies and Other Web Technologies. When you visit Airfarewatchdog.com, we may assign your computer a "cookie" (a small, unique identifier text file). For example, whenever you sign in as a Airfarewatchdog.com member, we may record your member ID and the name on your member account in the cookie file on your computer. We also may record your password in this cookie file, if you select the option to be automatically logged in. Note that member IDs, passwords, and any other account-related data included in such cookies are encrypted for security purposes. You can always choose not to receive a cookie file by enabling your Web browser to refuse cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies from Airfarewatchdog.com, you may not be able to access many of the travel tools offered on our site. We also may use Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or Web bugs) to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited certain Web pages on our site, and to understand whether you have come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party Web site.

Information Collected by Third Parties. Third parties, such as vendors, advertising entities, and business partners, may use cookies and other technologies (such as Web beacons) to collect information about your online activities. The purposes for collecting this information include: to measure usage of our site; to analyze, modify, and personalize advertising content on Airfarewatchdog.com and other sites; and to provide ads about goods and services we hope will be of interest to you. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features these third parties may use, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Some of these third parties may be third-party network advertisers that offer you the option of not having this information collected. To learn more, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**How we use your information**

Airfarewatchdog.com uses your e-mail address to send you newsletters and promotional e-mails. We use other information about you for the following general purposes: to provide you with the products and services you request; to communicate with you in general; to respond to your questions and comments; to measure interest in and improve our products, services, and Web site; to notify you about special offers and products or services that may be of interest to you; to otherwise customize your experience with Airfarewatchdog.com; to reward you as part of any reward and recognition program you choose to join; to solicit information from you, including through surveys; to resolve disputes, collect fees, or troubleshoot problems; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; to enforce our Terms of Use; and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection.

Please review "Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information" below.

**With whom we share your information**

Airfarewatchdog.com may share your information with the following entities:

  * Third-party vendors who provide services or functions on our behalf, including credit card processing, business analytics, customer service, marketing, distribution of surveys or sweepstakes programs, and fraud prevention.  We may also authorize third-party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including as necessary to operate features of our website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests.  Third-party vendors have access to and may collect information only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose.
  * Business partners with whom we may jointly offer products or services.  You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear with ours. If you choose to access these optional services, we may share information about you, including your personal information, with those partners.  Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party business partners.
  * Affiliated Web sites.  If you were referred to Airfarewatchdog.com from another Web site, we may share some information about you with that referring Web site.  We have not placed limitations on the referring Web sites' use of your personal information and we encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Web site that referred you to Airfarewatchdog.com.
  * Companies within our corporate family. We may share your personal information with our parent company and corporate affiliates, including Expedia.com, TripAdvisor, Smarter Travel, and Hotwire, as well as international corporate affiliates such as BookingBuddy.co.uk. This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services, both travel-related and other, which might interest you. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial e-mail they send to choose not to receive such e-mail messages in the future.

We also may share your information:

  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * When we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Airfarewatchdog.com, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Use and other agreements.
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

Other than as set out above, you will be notified when personal information about you will be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to have us share such information.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors our Web site receives or the most popular hotels and vacation destinations. This information does not contain any personal information and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.

**How you can access your information**

You can access and update your contact information and preferences by visiting the Newsletters page on the Airfarewatchdog.com Web site. You can close your Airfarewatchdog.com account by contacting us at the phone number listed below or by selecting "Unsubscribe Me" on the Newsletters page. Please note that after you close an account, you will not be able to sign in or access any of your personal information. However, you can open a new account at any time. Please also note that we may retain certain information associated with your account for analytical purposes as well as for recordkeeping integrity.

**Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information**

  * As discussed above, you can choose not to provide us with any information, although it may be needed to take advantage of certain features offered on Airfarewatchdog.com.
  * You also can add or update information and close your account as described above.
  * You have the opportunity to sign up to receive e-mail newsletters. As a registered Airfarewatchdog.com member, you can modify your choices at any time on the Newsletters page. You will also be given the opportunity to unsubscribe from commercial messages in any such e-mail we send. Please note that we reserve the right to send you other communications, including service announcements, administrative messages, and surveys relating either to your Airfarewatchdog.com account or to your transactions on Airfarewatchdog.com, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.
  * The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies from Airfarewatchdog.com, you will not be able to access portions of our site.

**How we protect your information**

We want you to feel confident about using Airfarewatchdog.com to help plan your travel arrangements, so we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no Web site can guarantee security, we have implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect the personal information you provide to us. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.

**Children's privacy**

Airfarewatchdog.com is a general audience site and does not offer services directed to children. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send personal information to us, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child to inform him or her that we must have parental consent before receiving his or her personal information.

**External links**

If any part of the Airfarewatchdog.com Web site links you to other Web sites, those Web sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend you examine the privacy statements posted on those other Web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

**Visiting our Web site from outside the United States**

This Privacy Policy is intended to capture information collected through our Web site from residents of the United States. If you are visiting our Web site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy.

**Your California privacy rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please e-mail User Support.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

Airfarewatchdog.com may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a notice on our Web site.

**How you can contact us**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [privacy@airfarewatchdog.com](mailto:privacy@airfarewatchdog.com) or:

Smarter Travel Media LLC  
Attn: Airfarewatchdog.com  
226 Causeway Street, Third Floor  
Boston, MA 02114
